BRYAN COPELAND

815 Avenue A, Scott, LA 70583 · 337-501-8695 bryan.copeland@me.com · https://github.com/djdizzyd https://community.hubitat.com/t/drivers-by-bcopeland-bio/

I am hoping to make a massive career jump into my new love (home automation development). I have been working in networking since 1996. During this time, I have had many development projects that were all in-house, and not published.

EXPERIENCE

11/2008 - CURRENT

NETWORK ENGINEERING/IT MANAGER, TANAR COMPANIES

Responsible for operation of network / servers for corporate network and customer internet services. Nation-wide fiber backhauls, LTE wireless networks and VSAT satellite system. Corporate and customer VoIP systems. Manage team of 6. R&D of products and services.

10/2004 - 11/2008

NETWORK ENGINEER, BROADPOINT

R&D of products and services. Maintained fiber network and VSAT satellite systems. Maintained corporate servers.

06/2001 - 10/2004

NETWORK ENGINEER, TACHOS LLC

R&D of products and services. Designed develop and deployed city-wide wireless broadband network.

EDUCATION

MAY 2019

SEC 401, SANS INSTITUTE

Security Essentials Bootcamp – Cyber Security Training

MARCH 2010

MIKROTIK CERTIFIED TRAFFIC CONTROL ENGINEER TRAINING, MIKROTIK

MikroTik router advanced QoS and traffic shaping training / certification

MAY 2001

REDHAT CERTIFIED ENGINEER TRAINING, REDHAT

RedHat Linux Certified Engineer training and certification

DEC 1999

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED SYSTEMS ENGINEER TRAINING, MICROSOFT

Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer Training and Ceritification

SKILLS

- Extensive IP background
- Extensive server experience
- Long history of R&D

- Work well under pressure and deadlines
- Thrive when challenged

ACTIVITIES

This is going to sound redundant as my only hobby at the moment has been smart home development. It's become my obsession.